Pooja Kakkalameli

DevOps Engineer | Cloud Professional

Bangalore, India | +91 7204544427

poo.kakkalameli@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/pooja-kakkalameli-b9489a64/

Objective

An experienced IT professional seeking full-time opportunities, with prior 5+ years of experience in Software Development, Cloud Operations, DevOps and an aim to learn technologies and progressive vision to contribute towards the growth of the organization.

Skills

- Highly motivated individual with excellent organization, communication & technical problems solving skills.
- Well versed with **Agile** Software Development Life Cycles (SDLC) model.
- Proficiency in scripting Infrastructure as Code in Ansible for configuring Kubernetes clusters.
- Proficient with SmartGit workflows SmartGit CLI and actions. Jenkins Pipelines in CI and CD for building and deploying docker containers.
- Demonstrated working knowledge as developer and devOps engineer for product of Cisco USA, SBI Banking Segment and Epiroc's mining software.
- An AWS practitioner and advance level of understanding with hands on experience.
- Well versed with concepts of Data structures, Algorithms and OOP methodologies.
- Hands on experience in developing C++ and Python Applications in Linux and Windows flat form.
- Experience in building and deploying large-scale C++ source code and various web application with high availability /responsive system. For clients like SBI [work at client location]
- On Site experience in Implementing **DevOps** for the first time in SBI ITFO.
- Keen interest in learning new technologies and tools.

Technical Proficiency

- Operating Systems Windows, Linux
- Programming Languages C++, Python
- DevOps Practices Jenkins, **Ansible**, **Kubernetes**, Helm Charts
- Other technologies Amazon Web Services (certifications in-process), EKS, SQL,
 Python and YAML scripting, Docker containers
- SCM Tools **SmartGit**, GitHub
- Utilities Make and GDB
- Ticketing Tool Jira

Work Experience

Epiroc Mining, India - Senior Software Engineer

DevOps Engineer | May 2020 – Present

- Developing mining features in Epiroc's mining trucks to minimize human workload.
- Managed SmartGit as SCM tool for the C++ code.
- Implemented python scripts to automate testing of the developed feature.
- Closed associated with hardware team for requirement gathering and to understand the model.
- Actively managed and monitored cloud infrastructure on AWS, EC2 and S3 including backups, patches, and scaling.
- Prepared and Presented SCM best Practices for implementing continuous integration for the team. Since developing team is new to the DevOps approach.
- Tools worked in this project are SmartGit, Pycharm, visual studio as C++ IDE, AWS and Jira.

Infosys Ltd, Mumbai - Technology Analyst

DevOps Engineer | Feb 2018 - Jan 2020

SBI ITFO – Implemented DevOps process On Site.

- First on-site project involved in all the stages of Implementation of DevOps from the beginning till the delivery of the project.
- Participated in requirement gatherings of various application deployment process.
- Developed CI and CD pipelines using CA Release Automation tool. -Nolio Agent.
- Presented demos to the client on various stages of implementations.
- Participated in all the Client Meetings and brief them the progress and infrastructure hiccups during the implementation.
- Ansible to automate image build and deployment process.
- Created Ansible scripts for Continuous deployment which update Kubernetes deployment definition files and apply them.
- Collaborated with multi teams and organization which handle different aspects in client location. Like IT team, Networking team, DB team.
- Tools worked in this project are Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, kubernetes, SmartGit.
- Agile Methodology.

Infosys Ltd, Bangalore – Systems Engineer

C++ developer for Cisco, USA client | Jan 2016 - Feb 2018

CUCM - This project involves development of the new features added as a part of voice-over-IP (VoIP) and also the sustenance activities of the key call processing modules of Cisco Unified Communications Manager (CUCM)

Applications developed and maintained –

- Analyze customer and internal issues on SCCP and SIP protocol related call Processing and its features.
- Mainly dealt with solving issues on Media streaming of VOIP such as Voice, video and conference.
- Develop the code and analyse logs/traces to find out the root cause of the issue and modify the code to facilitate the correct behaviour of the component.
- Helping team to resolve the issues/bugs.
- Debugging the functional issues and fixing the complex erroneous scenarios.
- Unit testing, Sanity check and Documentations.
- Sharing knowledge within team and across teams.
- Agile Methodology.
- Tools worked in this project are GDB, Make, wireshark, SIP and SCCP as network protocols.

Education

Dayananda Sagar College of Engineering, Bangalore

• **M.tech** in Computer Networks

2013-2015

KLE College of Engineering, Belgaum

• **B.E** in Computer Science

2009-2013

Hobbies and Interests

- Drawing and painting cartoons and landscapes.
- Like playing chess and swimming.
- Interested in home décor and gardening.